## Shubanker Chourasia

### Javascript Developer

Versatile Developer with around 5 years of Experience in building complex and challenging software projects. Strong banking domain experience for over 4 years. Specialized in JavaScript frameworks and building rich feature single page web applications.

subhankerchourasia@gmail.com 🔀

+91 7677155333

Hyderabad, India Q

linkedin.com/in/shubanker in

github.com/shubanker

stackoverflow.com/users/3623892/shubanker

#### . ....

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Analyst** DBS Bank

09/2019 - Present

Hyderabad, India

#### Full Stack Developer

- Designed architecture of a multi-tab based web application with Agular, Angular-Material and NgRx for back office Forex trading operations, enabling users perform multiple tasks simultaneously.
- Led a team of 2 & successfully migrated entire existing project features to new Angular application in less than 2 months.
- Designed a highly configurable dashboard system which enables users to get stay up-to date with task queues and perform frequent tasks or navigate to actionable page.
- Several instances of doing optimizing/refactoring of codebase leading to substantial effect in performance both in front and back end
- Reduced response time of an api from over 10 seconds to ~100ms by extending JPA and making count of a pageable query optional.
- Developed SDLC tracker with Angular and Ngx-admin to collect data on Applications currently under development from several sources & a customizable survey targeted for application owners, enabling management to easily track current stats based on several parameters, in broader as well as detailed overview.

## IT Analyst TCS

07/2016 - 09/2019

Hyderabad,India

#### Front end Developer

- Led a team and developed front end templates/components with JQuery, knockoutJS & bootstrap for an AEM project.
- Developed a documentation management for physicians, enabling them to pre-configure templates with set of questions based on their needs and getting fully dynamic form of custom data types to record patient data during consultancy.
- Received several recognitions and awards for performance throughout the tenure.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Engineering**

Durgapur institute of advanced technology and management

08/2012 - 06/2016

Courses

 Computer Science & Engineering

## **SKILLS & COMPETENCES**



### **OTHER SKILLS**

React, Angular-Material, Ag-grid, Java, Spring Boot, Docker, K8s, MySQL/MariaDB, Git, RegEx

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

BeeHive (2015 - 2016)

 Social Networking Application implemented with vanilla PHP and JQuery.

#### **Tabs-Counter**

 A JavaScript project to track number of tabs a user has left opened.

## Mdiary (2012 - 2015)

Developed a personal lightweight online notes/links saver.

#### **DynamicFields**

 A PHP class to replace original form field names with a dynamic field name and reverting back to original names in backend.

### **LANGUAGES**

#### English

Professional Working Proficiency

#### Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

Programming Astronomy Traveling

Swimming